好吧  就从我们到海边说起
Okay, so we went to the beach
菲比找到一个认识她父母的女人
because Phoebe found out about this lady who knew her mom and dad
然后我就不知道了
and I don't really know what happened with that.
我是你的母亲
I'm your mother.
莫妮卡开玩笑说  她不会跟钱德这种人约会
Oh, and then Monica joked that she wouldn't go out with a guy like Chandler
他一直很在意  然后我也不知道了
and he couldn't let it go, and... I don't really know what happened with that either.
罗斯的新女朋友邦妮跑来
And then Ross's new girlfriend, Bonnie, shows up
瑞秋说服她理了个大光头  然后罗斯和瑞秋接吻了
and Rachel convinced her to save her head. And then Ross and Rachel kiss
现在他得在瑞秋和光头女之间二选一
and now Ross has to choose between Rachel and the bald girl.
然后  我还是不知道...
and I don't know what happened there either...
等一下  我去找钱德来
You know what, hold on, let me go get Chandler.
嘿
Hi.
嗨  嘿
Hi. Hey.
瑞秋在帮我搽药  我的头晒伤了
Rachel was just helping me out. My head got all sunburned.
感激不尽   不用客气
Thanks a million. Oh, you're welcome a million.
好了  我得回房间了
Okay, I'll see you in our room.
天哪
Oh my God.
我知道
I know.
好  我走了
Okay, I gotta go.
怎么  为什么
What?. Why?.
我得跟邦妮分手
I got to go break up with Bonnie.
在这里  现在
Here? Now?
我不能整晚留在这里
Yeah. I can't stay here all night.
要是我回房  她会想...
and if I go in there she's-she's gonna wanna...
嘿咻
do stuff.
你不能说你没心情吗
Well, can't you tell her that you are not in the mood?
她喜欢那样
No, she likes that.
装睡也没用
Yeah. Faking sleep doesn't work either.
老实说  我经常早上醒来  发现她在...
I can't tell you how many mornings I woke up with her...
我说这个干什么  我不知道
Yeah, why am I telling you that?  I don't know.
并不是每天早上都... 越描越黑
It wasn't every morning... Making it worse.
《老友记》 第四季  第01集  水母惊情
Friends S04E01  The one with the jellyfish
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
我猜你大概想知道  前因后果
So I guess you'd like to know how it all happened.
我猜得到
I think I can figure it out.
我出生后  大家开始合起来撒慌
I guess You know I was born, and everyone started lying their asses off.
不是那样的...
No. It wasn't like that I...
我不是说过莉莉  法兰克和我很要好
Remember how I told you how Lily, Frank, and I we were, we were close.
我们非常要好
We were very close.
怎么说
How close?
我们三个是一对
The three of us we were, kind of, a couple.
制片：塔德史帝文斯
三个怎么会是一对
I don't even know how that would work.
我们... 我不是在问你
Well, we were... I'm not asking.
总之  我不知怎么的就怀孕了
Well, any how, some how I got pregnant...
我很...
and I was...
害怕  我愚昧又自私...
scared. I was stupid and selfish...
我才18岁  还记得你的18岁吗
I was 18 years old. I mean, you remember what it's like to be eighteen years old?
记得  妈自杀了  爸跑掉了
Yeah. Let's see, my had Mom killed herself, and my Dad had run off,
我跟一个叫山迪的人住在一起  他会跟他的手说话
and I was living in a Gremlin with a guy named Cindy who talked to his hand.
对不起  我以为他们是世上最好的父母
Well, I'm so sorry. I thought I was leaving you with the best parents in the world.
直到几年前  我才听说他们的事
I didn't even hear about your Mom and Dad til a couple of years ago.
当时  你已经长大了
and by then you were already grown up.
既然你来了 我也想多认识你
I don't know, you're here, and I would, I would really, I would like to get to know you.
每个人都想认识我
Yeah, well, everybody does.
我是个很酷的人
I'm a really cool person.
你有29年的时间可以查  但你却连试都没试
And You know you had 29 years to find that out, but you didn't even try.
知道吗  你扔下我不管  现在我也要这样
You know what, you walked out on me, and I'm just, I'm gonna do the same thing to you.
等等   我不想再见到你
Wait. I don't ever want to see you again.
我的皮包呢
Where's my purse?
讨厌   没有汽水了
Shoot. We're out of soda.
我去帮你买   真的
I'll go out and get you some. Really?
才怪  我又不是你的男朋友
Nope. Because I'm not your boyfriend.
菲比  怎么样
Hey, Pheebs, how'd it go?
我妈的朋友菲比  其实是我的亲生母亲
My Mom's friend, Phoebe, is actually my birth Mom.
我检到一个干掉的海马
I found a dried up seashores.
亲爱的   这是什么意思
Sweety, what are you talking about?
我的新妈妈  当年抛弃了我
My new mom, who's a big fat abandoner.
菲比  等等  你不想坐下来聊一聊吗
Wait, Pheebs, wait a second. Don't you wanna stay here and talk about it?
不了   我想静一静
No. I'm just, I wanna, I need to be alone.
莫妮卡
Monica.
结束了
It's over.
很惨吗
Was it awful?
很久
It was long.
我没意识到那么晚了
I didn't realize how late it was...
直到她头上出现5点钟的日影
until I noticed the 5 o'clock shadow on her head.
总之她不想留下来   我帮她叫了车   她刚走
Anyway, she didn't want to stay. I called a cab; she just left.
我写了封信给你
I wrote you a letter.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
我喜欢收信
I like mail.
我想了一些关于我们的事
It's just some things I've been thinking about. Some things about us.
在我们考虑复合之前
and before we can even think about the two of us getting back together...
我得知道  你对这封信的想法
I just need to know how you feel about this stuff.
没问题
Okay.
现在是早上5点半
It's 5:30 in the morning.
我最好赶快看完
So I'd better get cracking on this baby.
我等你  看完就上来
Well, I'll be waiting for you, just come up when you're done.
好  我要花...
Okay, I'll be up in...
十八页的时间
18 pages.
双面都有
Front and back.
好兴奋哦
Very exciting.
怎么了  你怎么没上来
What happened to you? Why didn't you come up?
看完了
Done.
你才刚看完  我想看仔细一点
You just finished? Well, I wanted to be thorough.
这对你...对我们显然很重要
I mean this-this is clearly very, very important to you, to us.
我想一字一句用心斟酌
And so I wanted to read every word carefully,
两次
Twice.
所以...行吗
So...Does it?
什么
I'm sorry?
行吗
Does it?
行吗  行吗
Does it? Does it?
我想再瞄一眼"行吗"的部份
Yeah, I wanted to give that whole 'Does it?' part just another glance.
罗斯  你什么意思  你说你看了两次
What are you talking about, Ross, you just said that you read it twice.
听着  行不行一句话  如果你还要考虑...
Look, You know what, either it does or it doesn't, and if you have to even think about it...
不  瑞秋  我不用考虑
No, Rach, No, I don't have to think about it.
事实上...
In fact...
我已经决定了  我决定...
l've decided. I've decided that...
这件事...
that it...
行
does.
你确定  确定
Are you sure? Sure, I'm sure.
好  发生核爆灾难  我是世上仅存的男人
There's a nuclear holocaust. I'm the last man on earth.
你会跟我约会吗
Would you go out with me?
我有罐头猩
I've got canned goods.
喂  你们看
Hey, you guys. Take a look at this.
你们瞧瞧  我挖了个洞
Check this baby out, dug me a hole.
好棒的洞啊  乔伊
Excellent hole, Joe.
不  我的洞
Oh, no. My hole.
我的脚
My foot.
怎么了
What?.. What is it?.
我被水母咬了  好痛...
Jellyfish sting. Oh, it hurts. It hurts.. It hurts..
要不要我扶你回去
Well, can we help?. You want us to take you back to the house?.
2英里啊
It's like two miles.
而且我挖洞挖得好累
Yeah, and I'm a little tired from digging the hole.
死水母
Damn the jellyfish.
所有的水母都去死
Damn all the jellyfish.
得想个办法
We've got to do something.
只有一个办法
Well, there's really only one thing you can do.
什么办法
What?. What is it?.
在伤口上撤尿
You're gonna have to pee on it.
什么  好恶心
What?.. Gross..
别怪我  我是在探索频道上看到的
Don't blame me, I saw it on The Discovery Channel.
知道吗  他没骗你  尿液里有氨
You know what, he's right. There's something like ammonia in that...
可以止痛
that like kills the pain.
我不要  其实没那么痛
Well forget it. It doesn't hurt that.
你可以躲进我的洞里
If you want some privacy you can use my hole.
我准备好要走了
Well, I'm ready to get the hell out of here.
你们...真的
Are you...?
太棒了
That's so great.
邦妮好可怜
Not for Bonnie.
但恭喜你们了
But for you.
海边好玩吗  不怎么样  我不知道
How was the beach? Nothing. I don't know.
怎么了  没事
What happened? Nothing.
我要去冲澡   我也是
I'm gonna take a shower. Me too.
我也是
Me too.
我把袋子拿到车上
Okay, I'm gonna put this in the car.
我得去收东西
I have to go pack.
真的行吗  行
And it really does? It does.
真的真的行
It really and truly does.
行你个头
It so does not.
（中央咖啡厅）
她要我对我们的失和  负全责
She wants me to take responsibility for everything that went wrong in our relationship.
她写了整整五页  说我如何不忠
I mean she goes on for five pages about, about how I was unfaithful to her.
我们当时分手了
We were on a break.
天哪  你再说一次我就跟你分手
Oh my God. If you say that one more time, I'm gonna break up with you.
分手不是我一个人的错  她写在这里
Fine. But this break-up was not all my fault, and she, she says here...
"要是你负起全部的责任"
"If you accept full responsibility...
"我就能再次信任你"
I can begin to trust you again.
"你想你办得到吗  行吗"
Does that seem like something you can do. Does it?
不行
No.
罗斯  你如愿以偿  跟她复合了
Look, Ross, you have what you want, you're back with Rachel.
现在提出来  会毁了你一生中最美好的事
If you bring this up now you're gonna wreck the best thing that even happened to you.
我知道  你说得对
Yeah, I know. You're right.
我会就此打住
Yeah I guess I'll let it go.
但你们了解这件事  很难忘记吧
But you-you understand how-how hard it is to forget about this.
当然很难
Sure, it's hard to forget.
但你不必拿出来谈
But that doesn't mean you have to talk about it.
这次度假有很多事
A lot of things happened on that trip...
都该从此绝口不提
that we should never, ever talk about.
在海边到底怎么了
What the hell happened on that beach?.
罗斯  那是我们和大海的秘密
It's between us and the sea, Ross.
乌苏拉
Hi, Ursula.
我知道  我们很久没联络了
Okay, well I know that we haven't talked in a long time
但我们的妈妈不是亲妈妈  另一个女的才是
but okay, our Mom is not our birth Mom. This-this other lady is our birth Mom.
对  住在莫陶克的那个
Right, okay, the one that lives in Montuak.
你认识她
You know her?
不认识  但妈的遗书里有提到
No. I read about her in Mom's suicide note.
妈有留遗书  还在吗
There was a suicide note? Do you still have it?
等一下
Hang on.
你居然没告诉我有遗书
I can't believe you didn't tell me there was a suicide note.
是啊  你最近好吗
Yeah, so how have you been doing?
我...闭嘴
I...Shut up
"别了  菲比与乌苏拉"  "我会想念你们"
"Goodbye, Phoebe and Ursula. I'll miss you.
"又：你们母亲住在莫陶克"
P.S. Your mom lives in Montauk."
这是你刚才写的
You just wrote this.
差不多是这个意思
It's pretty much the gist.
只差那首诗  你读过那首诗吧
Well, except for the poem. You read the poem, right?
没
No
那好  等一下
All right. Hang on.
请把起司传给我
Pass the cheese, please.
老天  你连看都不敢看我  对吧
My God, you can't even look at me, Can you?
不是
Nope
是菲比  我们可以跟菲比说话
Hey， Phoebe， We can talk to Phoebe.
我很沮丧  不想说话
No. I'm-I'm to depressed to talk.
我给你1千元开口费
I'll give you a thousand dollars to talk to us.
各位  我们要不要每年都回到海滩玩
You guys. what do you think about making that beach trip an annual thing?
不要
No
够了  你们到底出了什么事
All right, that's it, you guys， What happened out there?
什么  我们只是去散步  没什么
What? We took a walk. Nothing happened.
我身上什么都没沾到
I can back with nothing all over me.
拜托  到底是...乔伊
Come on. What happened? Joey?
好吧  不行
All right. No.
乔伊  我们发誓要死守秘密
Joey, we swore we'd never tell.
他们不会了解的
They'll never understand.
我们得说出来  我快被逼疯了
Well, we have to say something, We have to get it out. It's eating me alive.
莫妮卡被水母咬到好吧  好吧
Monica got stung by a jellyfish. All right.
我被咬到
I got stung.
咬得很严重
Stung bad.
站都站不直
I couldn't stand.
走也走不动
I couldn't walk.
我们离小屋2英里远
We were two miles from the house.
既孤单又害怕
We were scared and alone.
我们还以为死定了
We didn't think we could make it.
我痛得要命
I was in too much pain.
我刚挖完洞好累
And I was tired from digging the huge hole.
然后乔伊想起一件事
And then Joey remembered something.
是在探索频道上看到的
I'd seen this thing on The Discovery Channel...
慢着  我也看过
Wait, I saw that.
是探索频道  没错  它说要是你被水母...
On The Discovery Channel, yeah. About jellyfish and how if you...
你在自己身上撤尿
You peed on yourself?
你不能这么说  你不知道
You can't say that. You don't know.
我都快痛昏了
I mean I thought I was gonna pass out from the pain.
反正我试过  但没办法...
Anyway I tried, but I couldn't...
弯成那个姿势
bend that way.
所以...
So...
没错  我挺身而出
That's right. I stepped up.
她是我的朋友  需要帮助
She's my friend and she needed help.
如果有必要  我也会在你们身上撤尿
If I had to, I'd pee on any of you.
只不过...
Only...
我尿不出来
I couldn't.
我怯场了
I got the stage fright.
我很想帮忙  但压力太大了
I wanted to help, but there was too much pressure.
所以我找钱德
So I turned to Chandler.
乔伊一直对我大叫 "快尿  快点尿"
Joey kept screaming at me, "Do it now. Do it. Do it now."
有时在深夜里  我还会听到那个叫声
Sometimes, late at night, I can still hear the screaming.
那是我在隔壁吓你
That's 'cause sometimes I just do it through my wall to freak you out.
谢谢   谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
大家都回去算算房里的颜色吧
And I invite you to count the colours in your bedroom.
你除外  你给我滚
Except for you. You go away.
我马上就走
I'll go in a second.
我只想告诉你
I just wanted to tell you that...
我每天都在后悔把你送人
there hasn't been a day where I didn't regret giving you up.
好  再见
Okay, bye.
不  我还没说完
No, I'm not done.
我之所以没找过你  是因为...
I just want you to know that I, the reason I didn't look you up was because...
我很怕你的反应
well I was afraid that you'd react...
会跟现在一样
just well like, the way, the way you're reacting right now.
我们不能从现在开始吗
and can't we just, You know, start from here?
不行
No.
抱歉
Sorry.
最后一件事
But, it's not like we're losing anything.
知道吗  你来找你的家人
You know? You came looking for family.
我就是
I'm family.
没别人了
I'm it.
我说完了
Now I'm done.
我们又没什么损失
But, it's not like we're losing anything. You know?
你说得对
Yeah, I guess you're right.
我们又不熟  也没什么共同点
It's not like we know each other or have anything in common.
我不知道   我们不见得...
Well, I don't know. I mean it's not like...
没有共同点
we don't have anything in common.
像我喜欢披萨
I mean, I like pizza.
我也喜欢披萨
I like pizza.
是吗  等等  我喜欢披头士
You do?. Wait, I like umm, the Beetles.
天哪  我也是
Oh, my God. So do I.
等等  小狗狗可不可爱
Wait-wait-wait, wait. Puppies. Cute or ugly?
可爱死了
So cute.
看吧
You see?
但我还是很气你
But I'm still mad at you.
我知道
I know.
我也很气自己
I'm mad at me too.
你想吃东西吗  我有点饿了
Well, do you wanna get something to eat? I'm kinda hungry.
嘿  我也是
Hey. Me too.
好啦  你不用这样  现在你只是想让我高兴罢了
All right, stop it. Now you're just doing it to freak me out.
我好想你
I missed you.
我也很想你
I missed you too.
我对那封信好紧张
I was so nervous about that letter.
但是  你这么坦然的认错
But the way you owned up to everything...
证明你真的成长不少
it just showed me how much you've grown. You know?
大概吧
I suppose.
你有  罗斯  你不该妄自菲薄
You have, Ross. You should give yourself credit.
我妈一直觉得我们无法复合
I mean my Mom never thought this would work out.
她说 "狗改不了吃屎"
She said, "Once a cheater, always a cheater."
真希望没有这4个月的空白
I just wish we hadn't lost those four months.
但只有时间  能让你看清楚一点
but if time was what you needed just to gain a little perspective...
我们当时分手了
We were on a break.
要去咖啡厅吗  好
Coffee house? You bet.
这段感情会破裂  是两个人的错
And for the record, it took two people to break up this relationship..
对  你和影印店那个女的  你昨天表明愿意负责
Yeah. You and that girl from that copy place, which yesterday you took full responsibility for.
我不知道我负的是什么责  好吗
I didn't know what I was taking full responsibility for. Okay?
我没把信看完
I didn't finish the whole letter.
什么  我睡着了
What?  I fell asleep.
你睡着了
You fell asleep?
当时是早上5点半
It was 5:30 in the morning.
你一废话  就废话了十八页
And you had rambled on for 18 pages.
双面都有
Front and back.
还有"你得"  是指"你必须"
By the way, Y-O-U-apostrophe-R-E means "you are."
"你的"是代表所有格
Y-O-U-R means "your."
我居然会想跟你复合  我们根本就完了
You know I can't believe I even thought about getting back together again. We are so over..
无所谓
Fine by me.
你星期六晚上跟莫妮卡玩拼字游戏时
Those little spelling tips will come in handy when you're at home on Saturday nights...
一定不会写错字
playing Scrabble with Monica..
对不起
Sorry.
我只可怜你  会想我想到失眠
I just feel bad about all that sleep you're gonna miss wishing you were with me.
不...别怕我会睡不着
No...don't you worry about me falling asleep.
我还有你的信
I still have your letter.
顺便告诉你  这种事并不常见
And hey. Just so you know, it's not that common.
并非男人都会这样
It doesn't happen to every guy.
这是很严重的
And it is a big deal..
我就知道
I knew it.
我赢了
Gin.
我们在玩金罗美牌
We were playing gin?
知道吗  男女朋友会光着身体玩
You know if we were a couple, we could play this game naked.
别再说了  好吧
Would you stop? Okay. All right.
好啦
Okay. All right.
我觉得你很棒
I think you're great.
我觉得你人很好  很聪明
I think you're sweet, and you're smart...
我爱你
and I love you.
但你永远是在我身上撤尿的人
But you will always be the guy who peed on me.